Kieren Mcgill

Software Developer

📞 07542966439 . @ kacmcgill@gmail.com 🕜 linkedin/in/kierenmcgill.com

Sheffield UK

PROFILE

Software developer with 2+ years of experience in creating tailored web and software solutions across the development cycle, from initial client meeting to release. Specialist in JavaScript and Typescript, with a strong grasp of React. Excellent problem solving capabilities and trusted with leading the development of complex products. Valued as a confident communicator and team player, as comfortable meeting clients to discuss their needs as writing clean, maintainable code.

EXPERIENCE



Software/Web Developer

07/2023 - Present



Sheffield, UK

- Fully modernised website for major UK charity, using React and WordPress as a headless CMS, significantly increasing Google rankings and Core Web Vitals
- · Led major upgrade to a React Native app, leveraging Redux, geo-fencing and phone NFC APIs to enhance user flows
- Developed internal enterprise React app for major client, E2E tested using Cypress - used interactive Google Maps and company API integration to allow the client to generate detailed spatial data for sites across the UK
- Created e-commerce website using Remix, Strapi, Zustand and graphQL the site included a 3D product configurator using Three.js, authenticated user areas and custom invoice generation, with automation resulting in an estimated 500 hours per year of saved time for client
- Maintained a large-scale legacy PHP and SQL codebase for a major UK medical eLearning provider, significantly reducing monthly client support tickets by over
- Built excellent relationships via client-facing meetings and by providing tailored CMS training, receiving positive customer feedback for the studio as a result



Intern Web Developer

06/2023 - 07/2023

Studio Illicit

Exeter, UK

- · Built dynamic HTML components for commercial websites, faithfully following Figma designs to help increase productivity of senior developers
- · Used web analytics to identify and communicate performance issues on existing websites
- · Gained invaluable experience in how project managers, designers and developers work together



Trainee Software Developer

03/2023 - 06/2023

Sheffield, UK · Gained foundational knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, CLI commands and

- version control using Git, leading to the completion of a range of projects to showcase these skills
- · Achieved Certified SrumMaster status, then applied Agile methodologies when working in teams to complete projects
- Worked in Agile teams to integrate a React frontends with Java Springboot
- · Personally initiated relationship with a large education and conservation charity, allowing the cohort to build a QR code based trail app with a real-world application



Primary Teacher and Curriculum Lead

09/2007 - 03/2023

Schools in UK, China and Thailand

Various, Worldwide

- · Led significant curriculum change in large international schools, using collaborative and evidence-based approaches to ensure collective commitment from stakeholders
- Provided high-quality face-to-face training to large groups of teachers, resulting in improved results from lesson observations and greater confidence reported
- · Delivered online training for teachers across Nord Anglia's China region, spreading best practice across the organisation and raising the profile of our
- · Contributed to the strategic direction of UK schools through role as governor

CORE SKILLS

Frontend

HTML · JavaScript · Typescript · React ·

React Native · Tailwind

Backend

Node.js/Express · headless WordPress ·

Strapi · graphQL

Exposure

PHP · SQL · MongoDB

Interpersonal

Client interaction · CMS training ·

On-boarding and Mentoring · Leadership

EDUCATION

Postgraduate Certificate in **Education (Primary)**

University of Southampton

Southampton, UK

Bachelor of Science in Archaeology

Cardiff University Cardiff, UK

CERTIFICATES

Certified ScrumMaster

Scrum Alliance

Certified Full-stack Software Developer

Eyup Coding Academy

JavaScript Data Structures and **Algorithms**

freeCodeCamp

PHP Skill Path

Codecademy